Finding Aid for Helen Milliken Papers 1965-1982
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Helen W. Milliken Papers
1965-1982
1969-1982
Milliken, Helen (Helen Wallbank)
Civic leader, wife of Michigan governor William Milliken; topical files relating to Artrain, the Michigan Council for the Arts, the International Women's Year, Youth for Understanding, women's rights issues, notably the Equal Rights Amendment, and environmental protection issues; correspondence files; appearance files; and photographs.
85340 Aa 2
18.4 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Helen W. Milliken (donor no. 6863 ), and was accessioned through her administrative assistant, Mrs. Mary Browder, and Mrs. Phyllis Monroe, her secretary.
The collection is open for research.
Helen Wallbank Milliken, a native of Denver, Colorado, was educated at the Kent School for Girls and Smith College (B.A., 1945). After the end of the war, she married William Milliken, who she had met earlier in Denver.
In 1946, following his graduation from Yale, the Millikens settled in Traverse City, the home of William Milliken and the location of the family-owned Milliken Department Store.
Helen Milliken's interest in and involvement with Michigan politics paralleled her husband's rise within state government: his election to the State Senate in 1960, and his terms as Lieutenant Governor (1965-1969), and Governor (1969-1983).
As wife of the Governor, Helen Milliken was called upon to perform as Michigan First lady. In addition to certain ceremonial duties, however, she assumed other responsibilities and made significant contributions in the areas of the arts, environmental protection, and women's rights. She was an avid supporter of the Michigan Council for the Arts and served (since 1971) as honorary chairperson of Artrain, a traveling cultural exhibit.
Equally concerned about environmental protection, Helen Milliken spoke out on a number of issues--the control of billboard advertising, the prohibition of throw away bottles, and the restriction of oil drilling in the Pigeon River State Forest.
But without question, Helen Milliken was most outspoken on women's rights issues. She was a vigorous advocate of the Equal Rights Amendment, and wrote and spoke frequently on its behalf. In 1975, she made a tour with American Women for International Understanding to the People's Republic of China. And in 1977, she worked as convenor of the Michigan organization and delegate to the International Women's Year Conference in Houston. Beginning in 1978, she also served as co-chairperson of ERAmerica.
Throughout William Milliken's tenure as governor, Helen Milliken served in numerous organizations reflecting the variety of her own interests. Included were the Michigan Environmental Association, the Michigan Nature Association, the Society of Architects, the League of Women Voters, the Business and Professional Women's Club, the Federation for American Immigration Reform, Zero Population Growth, and the Federated Garden Club of Michigan.
The Helen Milliken papers total 18.4 linear feet of correspondence, organizational records, printed material, and photographs largely from the period 1969-1982 (though there are some items dating back to 1965). The collection consists of four principal series: Topical Files, Correspondence, Appearances, and Photographs. Preceding these is a file of Biographical Material.
Subjects:
Artrain.; Arts.; Civic leaders--Michigan.; Environmental protection--Michigan.; Equal Rights Amendments--United States.; Governors--Michigan.; Governors' spouses--Michigan.; International Women's Year, 1975.; Michigan Council for the Arts.; Milliken, Helen (Helen Wallbank); Milliken, William G., 1922-; Women civic leaders--Michigan.; Women in politics--Michigan.; Women's rights--Michigan.; Youth for Understanding (Organization)
Subjects - Visual Material:
Afro-Americans--Arts and crafts.; Art.; Artrain.; Children.; Cunningham, DeVon.; Kalamazoo (Mich.); Milliken, Helen W. (Helen Wallbank); Milliken, William G., 1922-; Project Head Start (U.S.)
Genre/Form:
Photographs.
- Biographical material
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Topical files, 1969-1982
  The Topical Files (arranged alphabetically) consist of correspondence, organizational records, printed material, and clippings on subjects reflecting Helen Milliken's interest in the arts, environmental protection, and women's rights. The principal subjects within this series concern Artrain, International Women's Year, the Michigan Council for the Arts, and Youth for Understanding. Other subjects (less heavily documented) include billboard control, the Equal Rights Amendment, the Pigeon River State Forest controversy, the Project on Equal Education Rights, and the Special Commission on Art in State Buildings. The remaining files are uneven in content. Some contain significant correspondence or policy-related records; others include only perfunctory materials.
  - Abortion (Letters Pro and Con), 1981 (Box 1)
  - American Artist Series (Box 1)
  - American Association of University Women, 1981 (Box 1)
  - American Women for International Understanding, circa 1976-1979 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, John, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Animals (concern for), 1977 (Box 1)
  - Art in the Governor's Residence (Box 1)
  - Art, Music, Drama, 1977-1979 (Box 1)
  - Artrain
    The papers relating to Artrain are the most voluminous set of files within the Topical Files series. Totaling approximately 4 linear feet, the Artrain files includes background material, records of meetings, planning reports, fund raising materials, scattered memoranda and periodicals, and correspondence (one group arranged chronologically, another alphabetically). There are also files relating to the tours made by the Artrain, scrapbooks of clippings, and promotional audio-tapes.
    - Historical Material
      - Planning Committee Meetings, April-September 1969 (Box 1)
      - Corporation Papers, 1971 (Box 1)
      - Revised By-Laws, December 9, 1975 (Box 1)
      - Organizational Relationships Chart; Directory (Box 1)
      - Committee Membership, circa 1971 (Box 1)
      - "Why an Artrain." Speech by Helen Milliken, circa 1969-1971 (Box 1)
      - Remarks by Helen Milliken. Greater Flint Arts Council, March 1, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Meetings
      - Board of Directors (Agenda, Minutes, Memoranda and Handouts)
        - September 28, 1972 (Box 1)
        - February 13, 1973 (Box 1)
        - 1975 (Box 1)
        - 1976 (Box 1)
        - 1977 (Box 1)
        - 1978 (Box 1)
        - 1979 (Box 1)
        - 1980 (Box 1)
        - 1981 (Box 1)
        - 1982 (Box 1)
      - Executive Committee (Agenda, Minutes, Memoranda and Handouts)
        - 1970 (Box 1)
        - 1971 (Box 1)
        - 1972 (Box 1)
        - 1974 (Box 1)
        - 1976 (Box 1)
        - 1977 (Box 1)
        - 1982 (Box 1)
      - Advisory Committee (Agenda and Minutes)
        - 1972 (Box 1)
        - 1973 (Box 1)
        - 1974 (Box 1)
      - Community Involvement Subcommittee Workshops
        - East Lansing
          - September 8, 1971 (Box 1)
          - March 15, 1972 (Box 1)
        - Marquette, January 9, 1971 (Box 1)
      - Corporation Officers, March 4, 1971 (Box 1)
      - Generator Committee, 1972 (Box 1)
      - Annual, December 9, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Reports
      - Study and Prospectus, Six Year Plan, May 1971-, June 1977 July 12, 1972 (Box 1)
      - President's, 1978; 1979 (Box 1)
      - Ten Year Plan, October 1981 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence (General)
      - Undated, 1969-1978; 11 folders (Box 1)
      - 1979-1982, 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Correspondence (Individual)
      - Cummings, Nathan (paintings), 1971 (Box 2)
      - Davis, Darwin
        - 1970-June 1971 (Box 2)
        - July 1971-February 1972 (Box 2)
      - Deer, Jean, 1971 (Box 2)
      - Doyle, Louis, 1969-1971 (Box 2)
      - Franco, Anthony, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
      - Harris, Robert, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
      - Henschell, William, 1971 (Box 2)
      - Jarrin and Leviton (Design Associates), 1970-1971 (Box 2)
      - McManus, Richard (Construction Chairman), 1969-1971 (Box 2)
      - Steffek, Ralph L., 1969-1973 (Box 2)
      - Sutton, Jack, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
      - Weddige, 1969-1973 (Box 2)
    - Memoranda (scattered)
      - 1968-1972 (Box 2)
      - 1973, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
    - Periodicals
      - Artrain News, Vol. No. 1-7, May 11, 1970-March 8, 1971 (Box 2)
      - The Caboose, July 1974; January, 1975 (Box 2)
      - Keeping Track, March 2, 1976; May 11, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Fundraising
      - National Endowment for the Arts
        - Project Michigan Arts Train. Proposal, December 1, 1968-June 30, 1969 (Box 2)
        - Meeting, June 11, 1970 (Box 2)
        - Community Involvement Project. Final Report, January 28, 1972 (Box 2)
        - Facility Construction Project. Final Report, January 28, 1972 (Box 2)
        - "Artrain America," A Proposal to Reprogram Artrain, circa 1975 (Box 2)
        - Storage and Maintenance of Artrain. Proposal, December 1, 1975-February 29, 1976 (Box 2)
        - Project Description: Proposal, January 12, 1976 (Box 2)
        - "We Celebrate Us," A Bicentennial Program Proposal, undated (Box 2)
        - Bicentennial Train Proposal, September 1975 (Box 2)
      - National Endowment for the Humanities. A Proposal for Support, April 1, 1971 (Box 2)
      - Bicentennial Planning Papers, 1972-1975 (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous
        - 1970-1971 (Box 2)
        - 1976 (Box 2)
    - Tours
      - Michigan
        - Schedules and Requests (Box 2)
        - Community Reports
          - 1971 (Box 2)
          - 1972 (Box 2)
        - Season, 1971
          - Detroit, September 21 (Box 2)
          - Escanaba, June 19-27 (Box 2)
          - Evart, September 12-16 (Box 2)
          - Iron Mountain, August 12-15 (Box 2)
          - Kalamazoo, October 10-17 (Box 2)
          - Manistique, June 11-15 (Box 2)
          - Menominee, July 2-6 (Box 2)
          - New Boston, October 22-25 (Box 2)
          - Sault Ste. Marie, June 4-7 (Box 2)
          - Sheridan, October 2-5 (Box 2)
          - Traverse City, May 21-30 (Box 2)
          - Trenton, October 29-November 3 (Box 2)
          - Warren, November 7-15 (Box 2)
        - Season, 1972
          - Fenton, April 8-12 (Box 3)
          - Manistee, August 31-September 3 (Box 3)
          - Western Tour, 1973 (Box 3)
          - Southern Tour, 1974 (Box 3)
    - General Files (including some administrative papers)
      - Clippings
        - Upper Peninsula, 1971 (Box 3)
        - 1969-1982 (Box 3)
        - 1972-1976 (Box 3)
          (newspaper supplements)
      - Community Handbook (Box 3)
      - Contracts, 1971 (Box 3)
      - Financial
        - 1971-1972 (Box 3)
          (correspondence, financial statements, memoranda)
        - 1976 (Box 3)
          (financial statement)
      - Insurance, 1971 (Box 3)
      - Letters
        - 1971-1973 (Box 3)
          (mostly children's)
        - 1975 (Box 3)
          (children's)
      - Printed Material (Box 3)
      - Prose for the Michigan Artrain written by Emil Weddige (Box 3)
      - Tentative Program Revisions, circa 1976 (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous
        - Undated (Box 3)
        - 1969-1971 (Box 3)
        - 1972-1973 (Box 3)
        - 1974-1976 (Box 3)
        - 1977, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
    - Scrapbooks
      - General (mostly clippings), 1971 (Box 3)
      - General (clippings and ephemera), 1972; 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Cass City, 1972 (Box 3)
      - Plymouth, circa 1972 (Box 3)
    - Audiotapes
      - Development of Artrain. Interview with Helen Milliken, Ray Scott, Louis A. Doyle,and Willis F. Woods, circa 1971; 12 minute audio; 7 1/2 ips (Box 4)
      - Promotional Tape, circa 1972; 11 minutes; 7 1/2 ips (Box 4)
  - Arts
    - Undated (Box 4)
      (reports on the Arts in Michigan)
    - 1976-1978 (Box 4)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - Battered Women Bill, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Battle Creek Civic Art Center, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Bicentennial (miscellaneous correspondence pertaining to Michigan celebration), circa 1973 (Box 4)
  - Bicycle Trails (legislative support for), 1973 (Box 4)
  - Billboard Control
    - 1968-1970 (Box 4)
    - 1971-1973 (Box 4)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 4)
    - 1979-1982 (Box 4)
  - Biographical Remarks by Helen Milliken (Box 4)
  - Bootstrap International (Box 4)
  - Bottle Ban (Box 4)
  - Braithwaite, Joyce (Box 4)
  - Bush, George (Box 4)
  - Cambodia (Box 4)
  - Campaigns (Gubernatorial)
    - 1970 (Box 4)
    - 1974, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - 1978 (Box 4)
  - Care, Inc., 1977 (Box 4)
  - Carter, James Earl (Box 4)
  - Center for Short-lived Phenomena, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Chairperson (Active or Honorary), 1969-1982 (Box 4)
  - Citizens Requesting Special Consideration, 1979-1982 (Box 4)
  - Committee for Gender Research. University of Michigan, circa 1982 (Box 4)
  - Constitutional Convention Implementation Act, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Damman, James (Box 4)
  - Davis, Darwin, 1971-1974 (Box 4)
  - Dayton, Kenneth (re Jan Vozewilcks), 1971-1973 (Box 4)
  - Detroit Institute of Art (Box 4)
  - Detroit Symphony Orchestra (Box 4)
  - Dinners (planning notes) (Box 4)
  - Domestic Violence, circa 1978-1982 (Box 4)
  - Easter Seal Telethon, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Echo Road Environmental Designation Campaign, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Ecological Studies of Wolves on Isle Royale. Annual Report, 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - Environment, 1976-1981 (scattered) (Box 5)
  - Equal Rights Amendment
    - Letters (Pro)
      - 1979 (Box 5)
      - 1980 (Box 5)
      - 1981 (Box 5)
      - 1982 (Box 5)
    - Letters (Con)
      - 1979 (Box 5)
      - 1980 (Box 5)
      - 1981 (Box 5)
      - 1982 (Box 5)
    - Countdown Press Clips. New York Times, June 10-July 10,1981 (Box 5)
    - Message Brigade, 1932 (Box 5)
    - "The Equal Rights Amendment," article submitted to Woman's Life by Helen Milliken, April 1982 (Box 5)
  - Family Planning (correspondence, statistics, and miscellanea) (Box 5)
  - Family Planning Center. Lansing, Michigan, circa 1975 (Box 5)
  - Federation for American Immigration Reform, 1980-1982 (Box 5)
  - Federated Garden Clubs of Michigan Landscape Critics Council
    - 1969-1970 (Box 5)
    - 1975-1981 (Box 5)
  - "First Ladies of Michigan" (correspondence re production of booklet), 1977 (Box 5)
  - Fletcher, Peter, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
  - Friendship Force, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
  - Ford, Gerald and Betty, 1974-1976 (Box 5)
  - Girl Scouts, 1972-1976 (Box 5)
  - Governor's wife (questionnaire on role of) (Box 5)
  - Handicapped Research Resource Catalog, circa 1976 (Box 5)
  - Heart of Gold Award Luncheon, February 10, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Ikebana International, Lansing Chapter (Japanese Flower Arrangement), 1977-1982 (Box 5)
  - Institute for Comprehensive Arts Planning, First Year Final Report, 1980-1981 (Box 5)
  - Institute for Family Research and Education. Ed-U Press Publications, 1971-1974 (Box 5)
  - International Women's Year
    The International Women's Year set of files within the Topical Files series includes ca. 6 inches of papers relating to the state planning conference for the Houston conference, the Michigan delegation's activities at the conference, and post-conference activities. Included are planning notes and handouts, transcripts, resolutions, correspondence, a brief diary, and an article composed by Helen Milliken.
    - Michigan State Conference Coordinating Committee
      - Planning Notes (pre-committee material) (Box 5)
      - Focus: Michigan Women, June 10-11, 1977
        - Conference Papers (Box 5)
        - Conference Transcript and Resolutions Report (Box 5)
        - Final Report (Box 5)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - National Women's Conference, November 18-21, 1977
      - Michigan Delegate List (Box 5)
      - Orientation Materials (Box 5)
      - Delegate Notebook (Box 5)
      - Proposed National Plan of Action, (Adopted, October 20, 1977) (Box 5)
      - Resolutions Adopted (Box 5)
      - Daily Bulletin, No. 1-3 (Box 5)
      - Leaflets and Position Papers (Box 5)
      - Newspapers Distributed (Box 5)
      - Milliken, Helen
        - Conference Diary (Box 6)
        - "The National Women's Conference," Media Spectrum, Vol. 5, No. 1, 1978 (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - Continuing Committee of the National Women's Conference
      - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous, circa 1978-1979 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 6)
  - International Year of the Child, 1979 (Box 6)
  - Japan (Itinerary for Governor and Mrs. Milliken), May 15-28, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Keep Michigan Beautiful, Inc., 1970-1981 (Box 6)
  - Kincheloe Airbase (controversy surrounding closing of), 1976 (Box 6)
  - Kirtland Warbler (gifts of), 1976-1978 (Box 6)
  - La Claire, David (photographer), 1970-1972 (Box 6)
  - Land Use (notes and remarks by H. Milliken on problems of) (Box 6)
  - Landscape Architecture, 1980; 1982 (Box 6)
  - Letters (special occasion congratulatory), 1980 (Box 6)
  - Mackinac Island, Governor's Residence, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - McNamee, Ruth, 1978 (Box 6)
  - Manistee Music Camp, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Marine Mammal Protection (Box 6)
  - Memberships (active or honorary), 1970-1982 (Box 6)
  - Merrill-Palmer Institute, 1977-1979 (Box 6)
  - Michigan Assembly, Women in the American Economy, March 31, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Michigan Child Study Association, 1974-1981 (Box 6)
  - Michigan Council For the Arts
    There is approximately 1 linear foot of papers relating to the development and goals of the Michigan Council for the Arts, and to the meetings of the Executive Committee, the Council, the Environmental Arts Committee, and various other bodies. The activities of the Executive Committee and the Council are so closely intertwined that the researcher should consult both if interested in one. And as Artrain once had an institutional relationship with the Michigan Council for the Arts, the researcher should be alerted to Artrain material here, especially in the 1970 Council Meeting folder.
    - Historical Material
      - Annual Reports, 1968; 1970 (Box 6)
      - "The Quality of Life." A Plan of Action (D. B. Varner, July 1969) (Box 6)
      - Brief History, May 1971 (Box 6)
      - "Here's What We're Doing to Improve the Quality of Life in Michigan,", August 28, 1972 (Box 6)
      - Transcript of Interview with State Senator William S. Ballenger, Member, Special Legislative Committee for the Advancement of the Creative Arts in Michigan and five (5) others, November 28, 1972 (Box 6)
    - Meetings
      - Council (Agenda, Minutes, Memoranda and Handouts)
        - 1970 (Box 6)
        - 1971-1972 (Box 6)
        - 1974 (Box 6)
      - Executive Committee (Minutes, Memoranda and Handouts)
        - 1970 (Box 6)
        - 1973-1974 (Box 6)
      - Environmental Arts Committee
        - Agenda and Minutes, 1968-1973 (Box 6)
        - Correspondence
          - Landscapers (Johnson, Johnson and Roy), 1970-1971 (Box 6)
          - General, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
        - Special Project Proposal (Artrain), March 30, 1970 (Box 6)
        - Memoranda, 1969-1973 (Box 6)
        - Miscellaneous, circa 1968-1971 (Box 6)
      - East Lansing (Agenda, Minutes, Memoranda, Handouts), September 20, 1973 (Box 6)
      - Bicentennial Committee. Minutes and Miscellaneous, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
      - Public Meeting (Agenda and Attachments), April 5, 1979 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence
      - 1970, 1973 (Box 6)
      - 1974 (Box 6)
    - Memoranda
      - 1971-1973 (Box 6)
      - 1974 (Box 6)
    - Periodicals
      - Newsletter, 1971; 1981 (Box 6)
      - Newsline, Community Arts Council, November, 1970 (Box 6)
    - Funding Proposals
      - National Endowment for the Arts, 1968 (Box 6)
      - State of Michigan, June 15, 1972 (Box 6)
    - General Files
      - Artworks, Michigan Congress on the Arts, June 15-17, 1978 (Box 6)
      - Design Michigan, circa 1977 (Box 7)
      - Finances (scattered) (Box 7)
      - Handbook for Michigan Community Arts Councils (Box 7)
      - Michigan Arts and Crafts, Fairs and Festivals, 1976 (Box 7)
      - Program of State Services in the Arts, 1974-1975 (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Michigan Council for the Humanities (Box 7)
  - Michigan Department of Mental Health. Women's Task Force. For Better or for Worse? Women and the Mental Health System, April, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Michigan Foundation for the Arts, circa 1971-1975 (Box 7)
  - Michigan Glass Month, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Michigan Rehabilitation Association Task Force on Women. Final Report, August, 1981 (Box 7)
  - Michigan Republican Women's Task Force (Box 7)
  - Michigan State Capital (history and tour guide notes), circa 1975 (Box 7)
  - Michigan United Conservation Clubs, Operation Cleansweep, 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - Michigan Women's Commission (Box 7)
    (annual reports, conference proceedings, printed material)
  - Michigan Women's Political Caucus, Grand Traverse Area (membership list), 1974-1975 (Box 7)
  - Milliken, Elaine (Box 7)
  - Milliken, William
    - Press releases and statements (very scattered; mainly ), July 1976; 1974-1979 (Box 7)
    - Gubernatorial Inaugurals, 1975; 1979 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence and remarks, 1972-1980 (Box 7)
  - Milliken, William, Jr (Box 7)
  - Miniss Kitigan Drum, Inc (Box 7)
  - National Convention of the American Iris Society, 1974-1976 (Box 7)
  - National Endowment for the Arts (letters supporting funding for), 1973 (Box 7)
  - National Governors' Conferences
    - Winter Meeting, February 25-26, 1970 (Box 7)
    - 1973 (Box 7)
    - 1977 (Box 7)
  - National Organization for Non-Parents, 1974 (Box 7)
  - National Peace Academy Campaign, 1982 (Box 7)
  - National Woman's Party, 1981 (Box 7)
  - National Women's Political Caucus
    - circa 1974-1975 (Box 7)
    - Republican Women's Task Force, ca., 1974-1980 (Box 7)
    - Nature Conservancy, 1979-1982 (Box 7)
  - Operation Understanding, 1968-1969 (Box 7)
  - People's Republic of China
    - Correspondence, undated; 1975-1979 (Box 7)
    - Michigan China Council, 1980-1982
      - Helen Milliken interview with Lucille DeView Detroit News, undated (Box 7)
    - New China, Newsletter of USCPFA of Greater Lansing, 1976-1977 (Box 7)
      (scattered volumes)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Peterson Wood Chip Company, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Phoenix Homes Project, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Pigeon River State Forest
    - Correspondence, undated; 1974-1980 (Box 7)
    - West Michigan Environmental Action Council et al. vs. Natural Resources Commission et al. Brief of Amici Curiae, February 23, 1978 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous (reports, proposal, speeches, etc.) (Box 7)
  - Platte Harbor (opposition to the Michigan Waterways Commission's plan for development of), 1973 (Box 7)
  - Political Candidates, Female (Box 7)
  - Population Explosion, 1970-1974 (Box 7)
  - Project on Equal Education Rights
    - Correspondence, 1978-1982 (Box 7)
    - Mobilizing Citizen Volunteers Statewide to Work for Equal Educational Opportunities for Both Sexes: Proposal for a Pilot Project in the State of Michigan. Submitted to the Charles Stewart Mott Foundation, October, 1978 (Box 7)
    - A Charge Alleging Sex Discrimination in the Rules, Practices, Governance and oversight of the Michigan Highschool Athletic Association, Inc., 1981-1982 (Box 8)
    - Administrative and Miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Quotations (of others, used in compositions) (Box 8)
  - Reagan, Ronald (Box 8)
  - Recipe Requests (sample letter) (Box 8)
  - Republican National Convention (Kansas City, Missouri), August 16-19, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Republican Women's Federation of Michigan. Bulletin. Vol. 12, No. 2 and 3, February, March, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Sargent, Francis W. (Women's Finance Division, Campaign for Governor of Massachusetts), 1970 (Box 8)
  - School Site Action in Michigan, circa 1975-1980 (Box 8)
  - Sex Education
    - Correspondence, 1978-1981